millenniumhotels.com 2015-06-13

# Privacy Policy | Millennium & Copthorne Hotels | Privacy Policy

## **Millennium Hotels & Resorts Privacy & Cookie Policy**

The Millennium Hotels & Resorts group ( **we, us, our** ) is committed to protecting and respecting the privacy of our customers ( **you, your** ), employees, suppliers and other parties.

This Policy (together with our Terms of Website Use available at <http://www.millenniumhotels.com/utilities/terms-conditions.html> and any other documents referred to in it) set out how we will process any personal information we collect from you, or that you provide to us.  It also provides information on how you may access the personal information we hold about you in order to correct or update it.

Please read the following carefully to understand our practices regarding your personal information. You accept and consent to these practices by visiting the following websites:

  * http://reservations.millenniumhotels.com
  * http://m.millenniumhotels.com
  * www.millenniumhotels.ae
  * www.millenniumhotels.co.nz
  * www.millenniumhotels.co.uk
  * www.millenniumhotels.com
  * www.millenniumhotels.com.cn
  * www.millenniumhotels.com.sg
  * www.mncloyalty.com

( **Websites** ; each a **Website** ).  

If you do not consent to the terms of this Policy, please do not access our Websites and/or provide us with any of your personal information while using them.

### **Sources of information we may collect or receive from or about you**

******Information you give us:** You may give us your personal information by completing forms on our Websites or by corresponding with us by phone, email or otherwise. This includes information you provide when you register to use our Websites; purchase our services, search for a product, place a reservation or otherwise enquire using our Websites; participate in any discussion boards we create or other social media functions located on or relating to our Websites; enter one of our contests; complete one of our surveys; and/or report a problem.

**Information we collect about you:** In addition to information you provide to us, we may collect the following types of information about you:

(i)  _Technical Information_ : including the Internet Protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet; your log-in information; browser type and version; time zone setting; browser plug-in type and version; operating system and platform; and

(ii)  _Information about your use of our Websites_ : including the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL) clickstream to, through and from our Websites (including date and time); services and/or products you viewed or searched for; page response times, download errors, length of visits to **** certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), methods used to browse away from a page and any phone number used to call our customer service representatives.

**Information we receive from other sources:** We work closely with third parties (including, for example, business partners, providers of technical, payment and delivery services, advertising networks, analytics providers, and search information providers) and may receive information about you from them.

### **Our use of cookies**

Our Websites use cookies to distinguish you from other users. A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers which is stored in your browser or your computer’s hard drive.

Using cookies helps us to provide you with a good online experience and enables us to improve our Websites. By continuing to use the Websites, you agree to our use of cookies.

We use different classes of cookies:

  * **First party cookies:** Our Websites plant these in your browser and/or hard drive.  You will be assigned a unique identity so we can track your journey through our Websites. First party cookies enable us to recognise you, and help personalise and manage how you experience our Websites.
  * **Third party cookies:** These are planted by parties other than us, often for advertising purposes or to enable a particular Website add-in to function. **** We have no control over third party cookies.
  * **Persistent** **cookies:** These are stored in your browser and/or hard drive between browsing sessions until you delete them manually or your browser deletes them in accordance with each cookie’s file duration. They allow our Websites to recognise you when you return to our sites, in order to track your preferences and tailor any particular goods or services for you. 
  * **Session cookies:** These are temporary and expire at the end of a browser session (i.e. when you close your browser). They allow our Websites to link your actions during a browser session so you can use the site more efficiently.

We also use the following specific categories of cookies:

  * **Strictly necessary cookies:** These are required for our Websites to operate e.g. they enable you to log into secure areas or use a shopping cart, as applicable.
  * **Analytical/Performance cookies:** These allow us to obtain data on the usage of our Websites (e.g. record visitor numbers) and how those visitors move around our Websites. This information helps us to improve our Websites’ effectiveness and ease of use.
  * **Functionality cookies:** These recognise you when you return to our Websites and enable us to personalise our content for you, greet you by name and remember your preferences (e.g. your choice of language or region).
  * **Targeting cookies:** These record your visit to our Websites, the pages you visit and the links you follow. We will use this information to tailor our Websites and any advertising displayed on them to your interests. We may share this information with third parties in accordance with section 4 of this Policy.

The following table sets out more information about the individual cookies we currently use and why:  

**Cookie Class**

| 

**Provider**

| 

**Cookie Domain**

| 

**Purpose**

| 

**Category**  
  
---|---|---|---|---  
  
1st and 3rd party

(Persistent & Sessions)

| 

Adobe Analytics

| 

All Websites e.g. millenniumhotels.com

| 

Analytics platform that tracks the performance of our Websites

| 

Analytical / Performance Cookies  
  
1st party

(Persistent & Sessions)

| 

Adobe Analytics

| 

reservations.millenniumhotels.com

| 

Track and support booking engine sessions

| 

Strictly necessary  
  
1st party

(Persistent & Sessions)

| 

Adobe Analytics

| 

All Websites e.g. millenniumhotels.com

| 

Support session tracking and improve user experience

| 

Functionality Cookies  
  
1st and 3rd Party

(Persistent & Sessions)

| 

Google Analytics

| 

All Websites e.g. millenniumhotels.com

| 

Track user sessions/engagement and interactions with our Website

| 

Analytical / Performance Cookies  
  
1st and 3rd Party

(Persistent & Sessions)

| 

Optimizely

| 

All Websites e.g. millenniumhotels.com

| 

Perform A/B testing and multivariate testing on web and mobile

| 

Analytical / Performance Cookies  
  
1st and 3rd Party

(Persistent & Sessions)

| 

Reevoo

| 

All Websites e.g. millenniumhotels.com

| 

Collect and record impartial product reviews from our guests

| 

Functionality Cookies  
  
3rd Party

(Persistent)

| 

Google

| 

All Websites e.g. millenniumhotels.com

| 

Track user preferences and information when viewing pages containing Google maps

| 

Targeting Cookies  
  
3rd Party

(Sessions)

| 

Microsoft.NET

| 

Reservations.millenniumhotels.com

| 

General purpose platform to maintain an anonymous user session

| 

Strictly necessary  
  
3rd Party

(Sessions)

| 

AddThis

| 

All Websites e.g. millenniumhotels.com

| 

Track social network sharing buttons

| 

Targeting Cookies  
  
3rd Party

(Persistent)

| 

DoubleClick

| 

doubleclick.net

| 

Retarget users who did not complete a conversion

| 

Targeting Cookies  
  
3rd Party

(Persistent)

| 

DigitalPoint

| 

.63mx.com

| 

Tracking platform to ascertain market share

| 

Targeting Cookies  
  
3rd Party

(Persistent)

| 

Bluekai by Oracle

| 

.bluekai.com

| 

Provide more targeted online advertising

| 

Targeting Cookies  
  
3rd Party

(Persistent)

| 

Live Ramp Inc

| 

.rlcdn.com

| 

Platform for targeted marketing and profiling

| 

Targeting Cookies  
  
3rd Party

(Persistent)

| 

Lotame

| 

.crwdcntrl.net ****

| 

Data Management platform for targeting and advertising

| 

Targeting Cookies  
  
3rd Party

(Persistent)

| 

Media Math

| 

.mathtag.com

| 

Display ads and retargeting

| 

Targeting Cookies  
  
3rd Party

(Persistent)

| 

Krux Digital

| 

.krxd.net

| 

Real-time profiling of visitors to provide more targeted online advertising

| 

Targeting Cookies  
  
3rd Party (Persistent)

| 

Cloudfare

| 

.gatag.it & .reztrack.com

| 

Overrides any security restrictions based on the user’s IP address and help speed up webpage load times

| 

Performance Cookies  
  
3rd Party (Persistent)

| 

Tube Mogul

| 

.tubemogul.com

| 

Video advertising services

| 

Targeting Cookies  
  
3rd Party (Persistent)

| 

Turn

| 

.turn.com

| 

Data Management platform for marketing

| 

Targeting Cookies  
  
You can block cookies by activating your browser settings to refuse all or some cookies. However, if you block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access or have full functionality and use of all or parts of our Websites.  By continuing to use our Websites without adjusting your browser settings regarding cookies, you consent to our use of the cookies described above.

### **Why we collect your personal information and how we may use it**

Our group companies (which means all direct and indirect subsidiaries of Millennium & Copthorne Hotels plc; **Group** ), may collect, hold and use information you share with us in order to provide our hotel services and products to you, including (without limitation) enabling you to make, and us to accept, reservations online for our hotels worldwide ( **Hotels** ). 

Our Websites allow you to communicate with us on a range of topics including, without limitation:

  * **Reservations and Pre-Arrival Information:** In order carry out our obligations under any contracts between you and a Group member, and to provide you with any information, products or services you request from us (including, but not limited to, processing your reservation), we will ask for your name, mailing address, billing address, email address, telephone number, credit card information, arrival and departure dates, and airline frequent flyer (or any other applicable customer loyalty) programme information. We may also ask for your room preferences and any other special requests or needs.
  * **Customer Service:** When you make a customer service request, we will ask for your name, mailing and/or email address, telephone number and any other information that will enable us to respond to your request or to resolve any problem at a Hotel. 
  * **Marketing:** With your consent, we may contact you about other goods and services we offer that are similar to those you have already purchased or enquired about, or with any other related marketing material.
  * **Electronic Surveys and Post-Stay Communications:** From time to time, we may conduct online surveys in order to evaluate our services and products. These are voluntary. To verify your identity, we may collect your personal information (such as your name, mailing and/or email address). 
  * **Guest Reviews and Other Feedback:** You may provide us with personal information when giving feedback regarding your stay at, or experiences of, our services and products.
  * **Contests:** Our Hotels sometimes offer special promotions, contests, or sweepstakes through which you can win prizes (collectively, **Contests** ). Each Contest will have its own set of terms and conditions, including particular entry requirements. By entering such Contest, we may collect your name, email address, and/or any other personal information we need to identify you for notification purposes.
  * **Events:** If you book an event with us, we will collect details regarding the event (such as the event date and time, number of guests, and facilities required) and, if relevant, personal information about individuals within the group. We may share your personal information with the relevant event planner where reasonably required to facilitate the event.
  * **Millennium & Copthorne Loyalty Club: **Enrolment in the Millennium & Copthorne Loyalty Club ( **MCLC** ) is voluntary, and subject to you meeting the MCLC eligibility criteria and agreeing to the MCLC Terms and Conditions. If your membership application is successful, we may, in accordance with the MCLC Terms and Conditions, access, review and update your personal information. You can also update your information by logging onto the MCLC website ([http://www.mncloyalty.com](http://www.mncloyalty.com/); using your confirmed membership number and password) and clicking on "Update my Profile".
  * **Careers:** We may collect personal information in order to consider and process any enquiries or applications regarding job vacancies at any Hotel or Group member.

By using our Website, you expressly consent to us processing your information for the purposes for which this information was collected (as described in this section of the Policy) and contacting you by SMS, email, telephone or any other electronic means.

Please note in some instances we may collect or be provided with personal information which is sensitive, such as your:

  * nationality (as recorded on your passport);
  * membership in a political, professional or trade association (where this relates to groups with which you are associated during any stay at a Hotel); and
  * health and/or medical information (where this relates to your preferences, special requests or needs).    

### **Disclosure of your information**

We may share your personal information with other parties where we have obtained your consent or, without your consent, with any Group member (including, without limitation, franchisees and managed hotels), and selected third parties including:

  * Business partners, service providers and contractors in order to comply with any legal obligations (whether under a contract with them or you) and provide any products/services to you.
  * Advertisers and advertising networks to whom we provide information in aggregate demographic and statistical form only (from which you cannot be identified as an individual) for marketing and statistical purposes.
  * Analytics and search engine providers to whom we provide aggregate statistical information, so they can assist us to improve and optimise our Websites.

We also may disclose your personal information to:

  * Any prospective buyer or seller in the event that we buy a business or sell, restructure or reorganise the business and/or assets of any Group member.
  * Any person, entity or organisation in order to comply with any legal obligation or regulatory requirement to enforce or apply our Terms of Website Use (<http://www.millenniumhotels.com/utilities/terms-conditions.html>), Guest Terms and Conditions (<http://www.millenniumhotels.com/utilities/guest-terms-and-conditions.html>) and any other agreement; or to protect our rights, property, or the safety of us, any Group member, our customers or others. 

### **Transfer and storage of your personal information**

Due to the global nature of our business, personal information we collect from you may be transferred, processed and stored overseas including (where applicable) outside the European Economic Area. Although the data protection laws of these other countries may not be as comprehensive as those in your own, we will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your personal information is treated securely, and in accordance with this Policy and any applicable laws.

By submitting your personal information, you agree to this transfer, storage and/or processing.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the Internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of your information transmitted to our Website; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

### **Third party websites**

Our Websites may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates.  If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that they have their own privacy policies and we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you provide any personal information using these websites.

### **Your rights**

We will take reasonable steps to ensure the accuracy and completeness of any personal information we hold about you. 

You can ask us not to process your personal information for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your information) if we intend to use, or disclose your information to any third party, for such purposes.

You may request access to, or the correction of, your personal information we hold, or to opt-out or change any specific marketing consents, by contacting us at dataprivacy@millenniumhotels.com. ** **

We note that additional privacy policies may also apply in certain circumstances, e.g. where you have agreed to our Guests Terms and Conditions, the MCLC Terms and Conditions, or where you have entered into another contract with us or any other Group member. Any additional consents you provide through other channels (e.g. guest registration cards at a Hotel) will apply.

To enable us to process your requests promptly, please provide full details of the particular information you seek and documentary evidence of your identity. Any access request may be subject to a fee to meet our reasonable costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

We only retain your personal information for as long as is reasonably necessary in the circumstances to enable us to fulfil the purposes outlined in this Policy, subject to applicable law. 

### **Changes to our privacy & cookie policy**

We reserve the right to modify this Policy at any time. We will post any changes on this page and, where appropriate, notify you by email. Please refer back to this Policy frequently to see any updates or changes.

### **Contact**

We welcome questions, comments and requests regarding this Policy.  Please contact dataprivacy@millenniumhotels.com.

This Privacy & Cookie Policy became effective as of **13 May 2015**.
